<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.7">Jekyll</generator><link href="https://ninjabot.me/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="https://ninjabot.me/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-10-02T10:01:33-04:00</updated><id>https://ninjabot.me/feed.xml</id><title type="html">OMG!ninjabot</title><subtitle>A random output stream of questionable value.</subtitle><entry><title type="html">reboot</title><link href="https://ninjabot.me/meta/2020/10/01/reboot.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="reboot" /><published>2020-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-10-01T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>https://ninjabot.me/meta/2020/10/01/reboot</id><content type="html" xml:base="https://ninjabot.me/meta/2020/10/01/reboot.html">&lt;p&gt;It is once again time for me to scratch that domain-registration itch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I often feel that I’m not a real nerd without a web site and my own domain, even though I rarely do anything interesting them. I don’t think I’ve put any effort into a site since the days of Tripod and Geocities. Back then the web was a new frontier for me and I found joy in learning new things about markup and scripting. My exploration of PHP and Perl to create dynamic web content was what put me on my career path. One would think that this would have created some lasting personal connection to the web, but one would be &lt;em&gt;wrong&lt;/em&gt;; for me it’s all business and no pleasure.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But sometimes there are things I feel like writing down and possibly sharing. Social media feels a bit too impersonal for me, so I’ll give this a shot.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">It is once again time for me to scratch that domain-registration itch. I often feel that I’m not a real nerd without a web site and my own domain, even though I rarely do anything interesting them. I don’t think I’ve put any effort into a site since the days of Tripod and Geocities. Back then the web was a new frontier for me and I found joy in learning new things about markup and scripting. My exploration of PHP and Perl to create dynamic web content was what put me on my career path. One would think that this would have created some lasting personal connection to the web, but one would be wrong; for me it’s all business and no pleasure. But sometimes there are things I feel like writing down and possibly sharing. Social media feels a bit too impersonal for me, so I’ll give this a shot.</summary></entry></feed>